white-hat-web-design.co.uk 2017-02-16

# Privacy Policy - White Hat Web Design

**PRIVACY POLICY   [Ver2] 1st April 2015**

This Privacy Policy applies to the entire contents of the website under the domain names [www.white-hat-web-design.co.uk](http://www.white-hat-web-design.co.uk/) [www.whdesign.co.uk](http://www.whdesign.co.uk/) (“ **the** Website”).

The Website is operated by White Hat Web Marketing Limited registered in England and Wales under Company Number **REG NO. 8714204**. The Company’s registered address is 89 Station Road, Sidcup, DA15 7DN, Kent (“ **the Company** / **We / Us** ”)

The Company is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy (together with our [**Terms of Business**](http://white-hat-web-design.co.uk/white-hat-design-terms-of-business/)and any other documents referred to on it) sets out the basis on which any personal data We collect from you, or that you provide to Us, will be processed by Us. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

**Using the Website indicates that you accept this Privacy Policy together with our Terms of Business Agreement regardless of whether or not you register with us**. If you do not accept this Privacy Policy and/or our Terms of Business, you must leave the Website immediately.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (“ **the** Act”), the data controller is the Company whose details are shown above.

  1. Information We may collect from you

We may collect and process data about you whether you register with us or not.

We may collect and process the following data about you:

  * Any information that you provide by filing in forms on the Website. This includes information provided at the time of completion on the Website, subscribing to our service, posting material or requesting further services.
  * We may also ask you for information when you report a problem with the Website.
  * If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.
  * We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.
  * Details of transactions you carry out through the Website and of the fulfilment of your orders.
  * Details of your visits to the Website including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access.

  2. IP addresses

We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about our users’ browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

  3. Cookies

The Website uses numerous cookies. A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we put on your computer if you agree. These cookies allow us to distinguish you from other users of the Website, which helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse the Website and also allows us to improve our site.

The cookies we use are “analytical” cookies. They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around the site when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way the Website works, for example by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.

You can instruct you web browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the Website. If you do not accept cookies, however, you will not be able to use the portions of the Website that requires you to signup or login.

  4. Where We store your personal data

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination within the UK. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to the Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

**We do not store credit or debit card details nor do we share customer financial details with any 3 rd parties.    **

  5. Uses made of the information

We use information held about you in the following ways:

  * To ensure that content from the Website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.
  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes.
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.
  * To notify you about changes to our service.

We may use your data, or permit selected third parties to use your data, to provide you with our services, for instance if We sub-contract elements of our services to such third parties (this is separate to third party marketing and/or advertising which is detailed below).

We may also use your data, or permit selected third parties to use your data, to provide you with information about goods and services which may be of interest to you and we or they may contact you about these by email, text, post or telephone. If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing and/or advertising purposes by default when we collect your data (the registration form) or alternatively you can also exercise this right at any time by contacting us in writing using the postal address found at the bottom of the Website’s pages.

We do not permit third party advertisers to display adverts on our website nor do we disclose information about identifiable individuals to any advertisers we may associate with unless you have requested us to pass on your details in pursuance of a service.

  6. Disclosure of your information

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case We may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
  * If we or substantially all of our assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our Terms and Conditions and other agreements; or to protect our rights, property, safety, customers or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

  7. Your rights

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data.  You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us in writing using the postal address found at the bottom of the Website’s pages.

The Website may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates.  If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.  Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

  8. Access to information

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

  9. Changes to our privacy policy

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted within this Privacy Policy and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

  10. Contact

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed. You should contact us using the details found at the Contact Us <http://white-hat-web-design.co.uk/contact/> section of the Website.

**Issue Date: [1 st April 2015]**
